<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>language on NoCE Lab</title><link>https://noce-lab.github.io/tags/language/</link><description>Recent content in language on NoCE Lab</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 07:37:59 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://noce-lab.github.io/tags/language/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Concepts across languages &amp; cultures</title><link>https://noce-lab.github.io/posts/research/multi/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Dec 2021 07:37:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noce-lab.github.io/posts/research/multi/</guid><description>coming soon</description></item><item><title>Concepts &amp; words across people</title><link>https://noce-lab.github.io/posts/research/langnetwork/</link><pubDate>Sun, 19 Dec 2021 07:37:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noce-lab.github.io/posts/research/langnetwork/</guid><description>coming soon</description></item><item><title>Learning words &amp; concepts</title><link>https://noce-lab.github.io/posts/research/learning/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 Dec 2021 07:37:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noce-lab.github.io/posts/research/learning/</guid><description>Our exploration of the dynamics between language and semantic, labels and concepts, includes the study of how the association between words and their meaning is built, as well as how developmet (and issues during development) affects that association.
Learning novel concepts Vigano, S., Borghesani, V., &amp;amp; Piazza, M. (2021) Symbolic categorization of novel multisensory stimuli in the human brain. NeuroImage, p.118016.
We used fMRI to study how the brain categorizes multisensory objects using words.</description></item><item><title>Loosing words &amp; concepts</title><link>https://noce-lab.github.io/posts/research/loosing/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Dec 2021 07:37:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noce-lab.github.io/posts/research/loosing/</guid><description>We investigate which neural substrate are critical for language and semantic processing. So far we have focused on:
the role played by the left and right anterior temporal lobe (ATL) in, respectively, verbal and nonverbal semantic (Borghesani et al., Cortex, 2019; Borghesani et al., NeuroImage:Clinical, 2020; Borghesani et al., Aphasiology, 2019) how ATL damage can be (partially) compensated by the over recruitment of spared dorsal and posterior areas (Borghesani et al.</description></item><item><title>Representing words &amp; concepts</title><link>https://noce-lab.github.io/posts/research/representing/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Dec 2021 07:37:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://noce-lab.github.io/posts/research/representing/</guid><description>We study the neuro-cognitive correlates of semantic knowledge (Borghesani &amp;amp; Piazza, Neuropsychologia, 2017). So far, we have seen how different concept features
are encoded in distributed yet specialized cortical representations, with crucial topographical dissociations describing a posterior-to-anterior gradient from perceptual to conceptual features (Borghesani et al., Neuroimage, 2016) are automatically and rapidly retrieved when presented with symbolic information (Borghesani et al., JoCN, 2018) according to the task the subject is performing (Borghesani et al.</description></item></channel></rss>